Dupont Park Civic Association 023
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Dupont Park Civic Association Records
1950-1980
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Dupont Park Civic Association
023
0.25 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Dupont Park Civic Association (DPCA) was founded in 1963 to combat neighborhood crime and to promote the civic welfare of the community. The goals of the charter were neighborhood improvement, property maintenance, and increased police protection. DPCA became involved with the Home Rule Committee in December 1964 as well as the Far Northeast Council of Civic Associations in 1965 to establish a program for community action against poverty. During the 1960s DPCA was involved with crime-watch campaigns to increase local police involvement in the area and Neighborhood Watch committees during the 1980s. DPCA also became involved with the Advisory Neighborhood Commission (ANC) 7D and other local civic associations to protest the District's proposed creation of drug treatment facilities and homeless shelters within the surrounding residential boundaries. DPCA acts as an advocate for residents on issues of healthcare, safety, education, traffic, and environmental issues impacting the neighborhood.
Custodial History
The records were donated by Joseph A. Glover, 1993 President of the Dupont Park Civic Association.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, by-laws, newsletters, and monthly meeting minutes of the Dupont Park Civic Association. Significant items in the collection include monthly crime reports issued by the Sixth District, Jesse Jackson's 1988 speech to seek the Democratic nomination for President of the United States, and the Far Northeast Council of Civic Association's proposal for community action against poverty.
Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; Crime; Citizens' Associations; Dupont Circle (Washington, D.C.); Newsletters; Minutes (Records)
- Series 1
  - Monthly Minutes/Reports/Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Monthly Minutes/Reports/Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monthly Minutes/Reports/Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership List, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Neighborhood Improvement and Police Protection Campaigns, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Home Rule Brochure, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Far Northeast Council Proposal for Community Action Against Poverty, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - By-laws of the Dupont Part Civic Association, November 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dupont Park Civic Association, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dupont Park Civic Association, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dupont Park Civic Association, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dupont Park Civic Association, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Monthly Crime Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Jesse Jackson Speech, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)